# **Brian Obindah**

Mobile 0721458867 Skype: brianobi2

Box 47936-00100 Nairobi, Kenya. brian.obindah@yahoo.com bruceobindah@gmail.com

# **Career Objectives**

Looking for a challenging Health and Safety consultancy position bringing my seven years compliance auditing and Health and Safety Management Systems implementation skills to a more dynamic and progressive organization which will provide me with an opportunity for career advancement.

### Education

2015 | Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Masters in Occupational Safety and Health

2010 | Kenyatta University, Main Campus

▶ Bachelor of Environmental Science (Attained Second Class Upper Division)

2004 | St. Mary's High School Mundika, Busia County

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (Attained B+ mean grade)

# **Work Experience**

2017 - To date | Senior Officer - Safety

Kenya Electricity Generating Co Ltd | KenGen HQs Box 47936-00100 NRB

Reporting to Chief Engineer-Safety

Main responsibility is to coordinate Health and Safety Programs in the Company

Conduct Health and Safety Audit in all KenGen installations countrywide

Conduct periodic Risk Assessment, identify controls and monitor implementation

Management Representative for Health and Safety Management System (OHSAS 19001)

Maintains Safety Section Budget

Coordinate Safety Training across all stations

\_\_\_\_\_

## 2015 - 2017 | Environment, Health and Safety Engineer

General Motors Corporation | Nairobi Assembly Plant Box 30527-00200 NRB

Head of EHS Department and reporting to EHS & Facilities General Manager

OHSAS and EMS Management Representative

Develops and reviews EHS Management System procedures and guidelines

Conducts Monthly EHS Compliance Audits

Incident Management and Incident Management System Key User

Conducts Process and Task Risk Assessment and maintain related documentation

Maintains EHS Section Budget

# 2011 - 2015 | Environment, Health and Safety Manager

Wartsila Corporation | Kipevu III Power Plant Box 81571-80100 MSA

Reports to Contract Manager

Developing, reviewing and implementing company Health and Safety Policies

Conducting safety inductions to contractor, visitors and new employees

Conducting Occupational Safety and Health training

Implementing Permit to Work and Safety System

Conducting Risk Assessment before critical jobs and designing and communicating Job Safety Analysis

Conducting monthly safety activities like Fire Drills, Safety Inspections and Plant Safety Meeting

Promoting first class safety culture in the company through role modeling

Reporting and investigating accidents and safety incidents, generating recommendations to prevent re-occurrence

Advising management on upcoming/new EHS legislations and action planning for compliance

Monitoring and trending air, waste, water and noise data

Secretary to safety committee, Security Supervisor and Transport Manager

Practical understanding of Health and Safety Legislation, Standards and Best Practices

#### 2010 - 2012 | Compliance Lead Auditor

Partner Africa (Kenya) | Westland, Nairobi.

Conducting Safety Inspections and investigative worker interviews during Social and Compliance audits

Remediation and training for Companies on various standards and compliance monitoring programs

Conducting Occupational Health and Safety Audits and writing audit reports

Conducting Trainings on workplace issues like discrimination, harassment and abuse

Conduction Environmental Audits and Social Compliance audits

Help companies to develop EHS Systems, policies and procedures.

Third party supplier compliance audits for Jones Apparel Group and The Coca-Cola's Company

## **Professional Skills**

NEBOSH IGC Holder

Permit-to-Work Systems

Environment Impact Assessment and Environment Audit

Workplace Incident Management Systems

ISO EMS 14001, OHSAS 18001 and QMS 9001 Lead Auditor,

Risk Assessment and Management

Quality, Environment, Health and Safety Management Systems

Environment, Health and Safety Auditing

Emergency Training, Planning and Response

**EHS Trainer** 

### Personal abilities and attributes

Communication skills
Leadership skills
Excellent Reporting skills
Team player and influencer

### **REFFEREES**

Mr. Simon Kirui

Chief Engineer, KENGEN

Mobile: 0727825040 Email: skirui@kengen.co.ke

Mr. Leonard Nawiri

Director, Ethical Trading and Social Assessment

Mobile: 0722687389 Email: robokendo@gmail.com

.....